<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Musings on Georgios Varnavides</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/</link><description>Recent content in Musings on Georgios Varnavides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 14:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Counting Digits of Pi</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/counting-digits-of-pi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 14:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/counting-digits-of-pi/</guid><description>Introduction As part of the MIT course 3.029 I taught in the spring of 2022, we held optional coding &amp;ldquo;get-togethers&amp;rdquo; once a week, alternating between &amp;ldquo;Data-Visualization Hour&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Code Show and Tell&amp;rdquo;. In particular, the week of Pi day happened to fall on &amp;ldquo;Code Show and Tell&amp;rdquo; and the students thought it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to code up one of the craziest Pi-related phenomena I know.
This is very beautifully explained in the 3Blue1Brown video below:</description></item><item><title>Generative Art</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/generative-art/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 14:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/generative-art/</guid><description>Together with some friends in the DMSE department, I&amp;rsquo;ve been teaching a generative art workshop during MIT&amp;rsquo;s Independent Activity Period (IAP) for the past 5 years. IAP 2022 was the fifth* iteration of the workshop (previously taught in 2017 and 2018 with Emma Vargo, 2020 with Amina Matt, Jovana and Nina Andrejevic, and 2021 with Jovana and Nina).
The 4-day workshop walks through python and Wolfram Language notebooks, covering the following broad topics:</description></item><item><title>Geograghic Map Distortions</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/geographic-map-distortions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 14:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/geographic-map-distortions/</guid><description>I’ve long been fascinated with transportation maps, and in particular the revolutionary re-design of the london-underground map by Harry Beck in 1933. In his iconic design, which has since been adopted by most transportation maps, Harry Beck deliberately sacrifices geographic accuracy for visual clarity of information - by using equally-spaced stations on straight lines with only 45/90 degree bends.
In this Wolfram Community post, we investigate how the local coordinate system is additionally distorted through the years as more stations get added to display the information more clearly.</description></item><item><title>Yoga Poses Constellations</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/yoga-poses-constellations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gvarnavi.github.io/musings/yoga-poses-constellations/</guid><description>At its first meeting in 1922, the International Astronomical Union (IAU), officially adopted the list of 88 constellations that we use today. These include 14 men and women, 9 birds, two insects, 19 land animals, 10 water creatures, two centaurs, one head of hair, a serpent, a dragon, a flying horse, a river and 29 inanimate objects. As many of us have (frustratingly) witnessed first hand while star-gazing - most of these bear little resemblance to their supposed figures.</description></item></channel></rss>