<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Topics on Georgios Varnavides</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/</link><description>Recent content in Research Topics on Georgios Varnavides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Electron Hydrodynamics</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/electron-hydrodynamics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/electron-hydrodynamics/</guid><description>In most conductors at room-temperature, electron collisions are akin to billiard balls, resulting in the macroscopic observation of diffusive flow (Ohm&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;law&amp;rdquo;). Recently, spatially-resolved transport measurements have revealed electrons in strongly-interacting materials can behave akin to classical fluids, confirming theoretical predictions over fifty years old.
I study these &amp;ldquo;hydrodynamic&amp;rdquo; electron flows across various length scales, from their microscopic origins, to mesoscopic finite-size effects, and to their macroscopic observables. Recently, I was part of a team which imaged these flows in a 3D conductor for the first time, corroborating a newly-proposed electron interaction mechanism mediated by lattice vibrations.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Characterization</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/advanced-characterization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/advanced-characterization/</guid><description>I have long been fascinated by materials characterization, and in-particular the ability to image atoms and nanoscale phenomena at high spatial resolution. One of the most versatile instruments to achieve this is the scanning transmission electron microscope (STEM).
In my PhD work, I have collaborated with experimentalists to directly image moirè superlattices at the interface of 2D/3D materials and investigate phonon localization at the interface between two 2D materials with high-resolution STEM-based techniques.</description></item><item><title>Spatially Resolved Transport</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/spatially-resolved-transport/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/spatially-resolved-transport/</guid><description>During the course of my PhD, I developed an open-source software package called SpaRTaNS to perform spatially-resolved transport by solving the steady-state Boltzmann transport equation in three real-space and three momentum-space dimensions.
SpaRTaNS is &amp;ldquo;carrier-agnostic&amp;rdquo; with applications in phonon (heat) transport (e.g thermal interface resistance of semi-coherent interfaces), as-well as electron (charge) transport (e.g the importance of microscopic interactions in electron hydrodynamic flows). SpaRTaNS can be run on anything from a laptop to high-performance computing systems, and provides a flexible API for specifying custom boundary conditions, collision operators, geometries, state spaces, and more.</description></item><item><title>Materials Science Pedagogy</title><link>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/materials-science-pedagogy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gvarnavi.github.io/research-topics/materials-science-pedagogy/</guid><description>I spend a great deal of my time thinking about pedagogy and the role visualization and computation can play in education. Currently, I am co-authoring an open-source materials science textbook with long-time friend and mentor Prof. W. Craig Carter. The idea is to curate some of the content we&amp;rsquo;ve developed teaching through the years, into a cohesive collection of computational notebooks which would guide undergraduate and first-year graduate students in materials science and engineering programs.</description></item></channel></rss>